Robert Beazley

robertbeazley18@gmail.com | 704-880-0586 Chapel Hill, NC

PROFILE:

Experienced professional making career transition into software development. Passion for web development with excellent problem-solving skills and resourcefulness. Proven ability to drive success and lead a team. Background in environmental compliance and utility vegetation management with highly effective written and oral communication skills.

EDUCATION:

North Carolina State University (2012-2016)

B.S. in Fisheries, Wildlife, and Conservation Biology-Fisheries Concentration

PORTFOLIO:

Coding Skills: Python, Django, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Git, Javascript, GitHub, Heroku,

Powershell, VS Code, Jupyter Notebooks, Pandas, SQL, AWS S3

Coding Portfolio: beazleyportfolio.herokuapp.com

GitHub: https://github.com/rbeazley18

CERTIFICATIONS:

• ISA Certified Arborist SO-10674A (2021)

NC Pesticide Applicator License: Right-of-Way Category (2022)

APPLICABLE EXPERIENCE:

Freelance Software Developer (November 2021-Present)

- Create and launch a functional and aesthetically pleasing web application for client utilizing Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Heroku.
- Utilize frontend web development skills to add additional features to the website, such as user-managed photo galleries and email communication abilities for site visitors.
- Optimize application for a wide range of screen sizes, including mobile.
- Troubleshoot bugs or site issues reported by client and implement fixes within code base.
- Effectively integrate services such as AWS S3, Twilio SendGrid, and Heroku.

Environmental Consultants Incorporated (ECI)-Raleigh, NC: Contract Forester (July 2021-Present)

- Inspect tree trimming and tree removal work on Duke Energy distribution lines in the Raleigh/Cary area to maintain grid reliability and safety.
- Communicate with customers and tree contractors to ensure work is completed in compliance with Duke Energy's specifications and to the satisfaction of property owners.

Curated.com: Ski Expert (October 2021-Present)

- Utilize communication skills and sales experience to sell ski gear to customers with Curated.com's online platform to create personalized gear recommendations based on a person's skill level, budget, and other individual needs.
- Continuously follow up with customers to provide support and assist with any new gear requirements or customer service issues.

CN Utility Consulting-Raleigh, NC: Contract Forester (October 2020-July 2021)

- Worked directly with Duke Energy in the Raleigh area to maintain transmission powerline reliability and safety through established vegetation management practices.
- Effectively communicated tree work to property owners and addressed any concerns using arboricultural and utility knowledge.
- Maintained quality of work and safety culture through tree crew oversight and QA inspections.

Environmental Consultants Incorporated (ECI)-Truckee, CA: Consulting Utility Forester (May 2019-August 2020)

- Contracted by Liberty Utilities-Lake Tahoe to work alongside the vegetation management department to maintain compliance with line clearance regulations.
- Improved grid reliability and safety through identification of trees that posed a risk to high-voltage lines.
- Effectively communicated with customers and addressed any concerns regarding tree work to be completed.

Phillips and Jordan-Raleigh, NC: Environmental Coordinator (May 2017-October 2017)

- Monitored site restoration progress on transmission line projects and created detailed reports that included the appropriate NPDES forms and photo documentation.
- Worked with a team of contractors and utility representatives to comply with line build specifications and maintain BMPs.

Foster Lake and Pond Management-Charlotte, NC: Technician (June 2015-April 2017)

- Analyzed the current state of ponds and lakes and developed strategies to improve the ecosystem.
- Completed stormwater BMP restoration and maintenance projects.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE:

Alpine Meadows Ski Resort-Truckee, CA: Ski Instructor (February 2019-June 2019)

- Taught adults and children the fundamentals of skiing through methodical progression.
- Effectively communicated techniques and skills in a group setting and provided individual feedback to clients.

Black Tie Ski Rental Delivery-Truckee, CA: Technician (November 2018-April 2019)

 Delivered ski and snowboard equipment to guests and fit them with proper boots and skis based on skill level or skiing style.

Alpenrose Gardenscapes-Vail, CO: Technician (April 2018-October 2018)

 Worked with a team to create landscape features such as flagstone walkways and decorative flower beds and performed regular maintenance on yards.

Vail Lacrosse Club-Vail, CO: U12 Coach (Spring 2018)

• Taught players the fundamentals of lacrosse and emphasized the importance of teamwork and sportsmanship throughout the season.

Vail Ski Resort-Vail, CO: Mountain Safety (November 2017-April 2018)

- Interacted with guests to educate them on how to ski or ride in the safest way possible.
- Worked with a team to set up preventive measures around the mountain to help reduce accidents.
- Helped host safety-related events to raise awareness of safety on the mountain.

Rowboat Dock and Dredge-Mooresville, NC: Laborer (Summer 2012, 2013)

- Worked with a team to frame and deck docks.
- Operated forklift, skid-steer, and other heavy equipment.

SCHOLARSHIPS & AWARDS:

- Chancellor's Leadership Scholarship (2012)
- Eagle Scout (2009)